Guide to the Enoch Hale Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
Enoch Hale Papers
1764-1980
RG 66
Yale University Divinity School Library
4
(10 boxes)
Correspondence relates to Hale's roles as minister, father, educator, Secretary of the General Association of Congregational Churches and Ministers of Massachusetts, and Secretary of the Hampshire Missionary Society. Diaries contain brief daily entries describing the weather, notable activities and events, sermons written and preached, town meetings attended, marriages performed, visitors received, journeys taken and chores performed. Also included is information regarding births and deaths in Westhampton. The diaries provide fifty years of consistent and valuable documentation of the daily activities of a Congregational minister in a small New England town. Notes and memoranda reflect Hale's interest in politics, his administrative and ministerial duties, and Biblical studies. Over 1200 sermons with indexes are included. Enoch Hale, born in Coventry, Connecticut on October 28, 1753, was the brother of the famed Nathan Hale. He graduated from Yale College in 1773 and served as a Congregational clergyman in Westhampton, Massachusetts from 1778-1828. He also served as Secretary of the General Association of the Congregational Churches and Ministers of Massachusetts from 1804-1824, and was Secretary of the Hampshire Missionary Society for many years. He was involved in the educational and public interests of his community and represented Westhampton in the State Constitutional Convention of 1820. He died on January 19, 1837.
Hale, Enoch, 1753-1837
Conditions Governing Access
Open to qualified researchers.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of the Westhampton Congregational Church, Westhampton, Massachusetts, 1980
Biographical / Historical
1753 Oct 28 Born in Coventry, CT, son of Richard and Elizabeth Hale
1773 Graduated from Yale College. Taught school near Windsor, CT, and studied theology
1775 Licensed to preach by Windham County Association of Ministers
1778 Nov Began preaching in Westhampton, MA
1779 Sep Ordained; Hale served the Congregational church in Westhampton for fifty years. He was involved in the educational and public interests of his community, serving, for example, as the representative of the town in the State Constitutional Convention of 1820. He was Secretary of the General Association of the Congregational Churches and Ministers of Massachusetts from 1804 to 1824. He also served as Secretary of the Hampshire Missionary Society for many years and took occasional mission trips.
1781 Married Octavia Throop: eight children. Eldest son named Nathan Hale after Enoch's famous younger brother
1799 Published A Spelling Book; or the First Part of a Grammar of the English language, as written and spoken in the United States
1804 Published Asking Amiss and Not Receiving, a sermon preached 1804 Apr 5
1837 Jan 19 Died
Biographical information taken from: Yale Biographies and Annals 1763-1778, by Franklin Bowditch Dexter
Scope and Contents
I. Correspondence, 1778-1832.
II. Diaries, ca. 1773-1833.
III. Notes and Memoranda, 1773-1980, n.d.
IV. Sermons, 1764-1833, n.d.
The letters of Series I date from 1778 to 1832 and are all addressed to Enoch Hale, with the exception of four. In content, the letters relate to Hale's roles as minister, father, educator, Secretary of the General Association of Congregational Churches and Ministers of Massachusetts, and Secretary of the Hampshire Missionary Society. As minister of the Congregational Church of Westhampton, Hale received letters from other Congregational churches throughout New England and from individuals seeking transfer of church membership. In most cases there are only one or two letters from each of Hale's correspondents. A total of fifty-seven letters of Hale's eldest son, Nathan, span the years 1814 to 1826. They touch on family matters and on the younger Hale's work in Boston as a lawyer and editor of the Daily Advertiser. In a few cases the letters are actually written by Nathan's wife, Sarah, on his behalf. Among Enoch Hale's more prominent correspondents were Jeremiah Evarts (1 letter) and Jedidiah Morse (3 letters).
The diaries of Series II contain very brief daily entries describing the weather and notable activities or events. The earliest diary, which was identified only as "Hale college diary", has entries of a few words for each day. Diaries from the years 1776 to 1780 are available only on microfilm. The originals of these diaries were evidently removed from the Westhampton Congregational Church at some earlier time and are held at the David Library of the American Revolution in Washington Crossing, Pennsylvania. Beginning with 1783, diaries are available for each year until 1833, with the exception of the year 1793. The entries in the later diaries are somewhat longer, always reporting the weather, but also touching on sermons written and preached, town meetings attended, marriages performed, visitors received, etc. At the end of each diary, Hale wrote a page or more of summary notes, indicating the most notable events of the year and including information regarding births and deaths in the town of Westhampton. These diaries provide fifty years of consistent and valuable documentation of the daily activities of a Congregational minister in a small New England town.
The notes and memoranda of Series III are a mixture of varying interest. Some are fragmentary and difficult to identify, but as a body they serve to shed light on various aspects of Hale's career. Hale's interest in politics, his administrative duties, his ministerial activities, and his interpretation of Biblical passages are documented. The material related to the Westhampton Congregational Church includes a few items from after Hale's death, and the 1980 church bulletin recording the transferral of the Hale Papers to the Yale Divinity School Library.
Series IV, the largest of this record group, contains more than 1200 sermons, most of which are arranged chronologically in two numerical sequences. The sermons vary in length from four pages to more than twenty, and are written in legible handwriting. Some of the sermons have suffered water damage and are difficult to decipher. The date and location where the sermon was preacher is generally noted on the first page. No sermons exist for the period 1793 to 1810. The earliest sermon in the chronological sequence is quite certainly not authored by Hale, as he would have been only eleven years old in 1764. In the first folder of this series are detailed registers indexing the sermons. A chronological register records sermons from 1777 to 1833. More fragmentary indices according to Biblical texts are available for some of the years between 1810 and 1829. At the end of this series are undated, unnumbered sermons and sermon fragments, ten charges to new ministers, and the published record of the sermon, charge, and right hand of fellowship at the ordination of Enoch Hale in 1779.
Arrangement
I. Correspondence, 1778-1832
II. Diaries, ca. 1773-1833
III. Notes and Memoranda, 1773-1980, n.d.
IV. Sermons, 1764-1833, n.d.
Congregational churches -- Massachusetts; Religion and politics; Sermons, American; Weather; Massachusetts -- History; Massachusetts -- Religion; United States -- Religion; Diaries; Sermons; Clergy; Hale, Enoch, 1753-1837; Hale, Nathan, 1784-1863; General Association of Congregational Churches and Ministers of Massachusetts; Hampshire Missionary Society; Westhampton Congregational Church (Westhampton, Mass.)
- Correspondence, 1778-1832; Series I
  Scope and Contents
  The location from which the correspondence was sent follows each entry.
  - Abbot, J. / (sent from) Amherst, 1828 Dec 12 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Armstrong, Samuel T. / Boston, 1816 Aug 19 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Association of Ministers in Franklin County / Heath, 1817 Mar 24 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Avery, David / Northampton, 1816 Dec 25 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Baldwin, T. / Boston, 1824 May 4 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Bates, I. C. / Washington, 1829 Jan 14; 1830 Jan 4 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Bates, Lemuel / Whately, 1829 Mar 12 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Beach, George / Hartford, 1826 Feb 7 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Berkshire Association / Pittsfield, 1817 Feb 28 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Bliss, George, Jr. / Springfield, 1826 Nov 1 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Bodman, Joseph / Williamsburg, 1831 May 20 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Bond, Alvan / Sturbridge, 1824 Aug 16 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Bound, John / Northampton, 1814 Sep 25 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Brewer, Jonas / Westhampton, 1828 Jul 10 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Cannon, Josiah W. / Amherst, 1810 Jan 17 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Chapin, Horace B. / Bennington, VT; Hadley, 1829 May 25, 1829 Jun 10 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Chickering, Joseph / Woburn, 1813 Aug 7 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Church of Christ in Hatfield / Hatfield, 1827 Jan 3 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Church of Christ in Northampton / Northampton, 1824 Feb 23 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Church of Christ in Norwich / Norwich, 1831 Jun 28 1832 Aug 20 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Church of Christ in Southampton / Southampton, 1832 Jan 4 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Church of Christ in Stockbridge / Stockbridge, 1817 Jun 14 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Claflin, L. F. / Pittsfield, 1830 Mar 22 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Clapp, Bela P. / Westhampton, 1827 Mar 17 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Clark, Dorus / Boston, Beverly, 1819 Jan 28, 1820 May 10 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Coleman, Lyman / Belchertown, 1829 Mar 4, Apr 27 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Cook, Phinehas / Acworth; Lebanon, 1829 Feb 20, Mar 6, Apr 6 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Cooley, Timothy N. / Granville, 1816 Apr 9 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Cragin, John / Temple, NH, 1778 Sep 1 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Edwards, B. B. / Amherst, 1827 Jun 16 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Ely, William / Washington, 1815 Feb 17 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Evarts, Jeremiah / Charlestown, 1813 Jun 19 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - First Congregational Church and Society / Northampton, 1832 Mar 11 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Garvin, Isaac / Butterworth, 1817 Jul (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Gould, Vinson / Southampton, 1828 Apr 21, Jun 26, Jul 28 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Griswold, J. F. / South Hadley Canal, 1830 Apr 6 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Hale, Nathan (son) / Boston, 1814-1815 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Hale, Nathan (son) / Boston, 1816-1819 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Hale, Nathan (son) / Boston, 1820-1821 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Hale, Nathan (son) / Boston, 1822-1823 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Hale, Nathan (son) / Boston, 1824-1826 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Hawes, J. / Hartford, 1829 May 15 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Hopkins, John / Boston, 1816 Nov 27 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Howard, Bezaleel / Springfield, 1816 Nov 18 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - to the inhabitants of Westhampton / from E. Hale (Westhampton), 1811 Apr 1 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Judd, Jonathan (see also: Hawes, J.) / Hartford, 1828 Nov 24 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - to Judd, Jonathan / from E. Hale, 1802 May 29 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Knapp, Isaac / Westfield, 1829 Jul 29 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Knight, Caleb / Washington, 1832 Feb 16 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Lathrop, Joseph / W. Springfield, 1817 Jan 7 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Lesslie, Jonathan / Harpersfield, 1814 May (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Lewis, Wales / Northampton, 1826 Mar 21 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Loomis, Amasa / Painesville, OH, 1818 May 28 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Ludlow, H. G. / New York, 1830 Oct 12 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Lyman, Joseph / Hatfield, 1812 May 20 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Mann, Cyrus / Westminster, 1824 Apr 12 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Massachusetts Society for Promoting Agriculture / Boston, 1813 Mar 15 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Mayhew, Willmot / Gill, 1817 Nov 13 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Mead, Samuel / Amesbury, 1817 Jan 23 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Morse, Jedidiah / Charlestown, 1814 Nov 21 1815 Feb 16 1816 Jun 24 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Newman, M. / Andover, 1814 Jan 22 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Northrop, B. F. / Manchester, 1828 Nov 26 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Norton, Elijah / Westhampton, 1820 Dec 18 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Oliphant, David / Beverly, 1823 Aug 18 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Osgood, Erastus / Lebanon, 1815 May 6 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - to Panoplist and Missionary Magazine editors / from E. Hale (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Partridge, J. L. / Northampton, 1828 May 27 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Perkins, Nathan / Amherst, 1813 Aug 22 1829 Mar 6, Jun 3 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Pond, Enoch / Boston, 1831 Feb 21 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Porter, Experience / Belchertown, 1816 Dec 3 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - to Rand, Thomas / from E. Hale, 1820 Jun 12 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Scott, Jonathan / Minot, ME, 1803-1812 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Second Congregational Church in Deerfield / Deerfield, 1827 Aug 28 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Shepard, Thomas / Ashfield, 1822 May 22 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Smith, Hervey / Westhampton, 1824 Nov 16 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Stoddard, C. / Boston, 1825 Dec 2 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Stoddard, S., Jr. / Boston, 1823 Jun 12 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Strong, Joseph / Norwich, 1829 Jan 19 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Sylvester, Eliakim / Chesterfield, 1814 Sep 18 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Treasury Department / Washington, D. C., 1824 Sep 23 1825 Nov 23 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Truair, John / Northampton, 1825 Mar 16, Dec 20 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Tucker, James / Rowley, 1815 May 2 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Tucker, Mark / Northampton, 1825 Mar 30, Apr 13; 1826 Oct 24 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Waters, Ira / Chesterfield, 1831 Apr 26 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Whitmarsh, Alva / Springfield, 1821 Jan 3 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Whitney, D. S. / Northampton, 1824-1829 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Williams, E. / Northampton, 1828 Jun 6 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Williams, Solomon / Northampton, 1827 Jan 8, Apr 10 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Williams, Thomas / South St. Lowis (?), 1811 Feb 16 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Williston, P. / Easthampton, 1824 Apr 7 1828 Aug 25 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Woodbridge, John / Hadley, 1828 May 31 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Yeomans, J. W. / North Adams, 1828 May 30 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Diaries, ca. 1773-1833; Series II
  The diaries are arranged chronologically.
  - Diaries -originals, ca. 1773, 1783-1789 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Diaries - on microfilm, 1776-1780 (Box 2A, Folder 20a)
  - Diaries - originals, 1790-1792, 1794-1833 (Box 2, Folder 21-27)
- Notes and Memoranda, 1773-1980, n.d.; Series III
  The notes and memoranda are arranged topically, with dates and numbers of items indicated.
  - Confessions of Faith and Church Covenants (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Lists of members of state and national Congresses, 1820-1828 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Material related to General Association of Massachusetts, Hampshire Education Society and Hampshire Missionary Society, 1815, 1822, 1825, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Material related to Westhampton Congregational Church, 1818-1980, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Miscellaneous and unidentified records and notes, including re. land ownership of EH, location of planets, money received after EH house destroyed by fire, the English attack on New Orleans, the death of A.G. Bridgeman., 1773-1826 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Miscellaneous notes on Biblical texts, 1817-1824 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Manuscript on English grammar, possibly related to Hale's publication on that subject (1799), n.d. (Box 2, Folder 34)
- Sermons, 1764-1833, n.d; Series IV
  The first folder of this Series contains a chronological register of sermons preached by Hale and registers by Biblical text. These are followed by seven early sermons dating 1764-1786, not all of which are by Hale. Hale's first numerical sequence begins in 1789 with #1033 and ends in 1816 wtih #3533, with a large gap between #1299 and #3113. A new numerical sequence was begun in 1817 extending with only small gaps until #1327 in 1833.
  - Chronological register of sermons, 1777-1833 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Registers of sermons by text, 1810-1829, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Early sermons (probably not all by EH), 1764-1786 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Sermons #1033, 1035-1038, 1041-1043, 1046, 1047, 1049-1052, 1 unnumbered, 1789 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - #1053-1067, 1789 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - #1069-1081, 1789 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - #1082-1091, 1789 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - #1092-1105, 1790 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - #1106-1119, 1121-1127, 1790 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - #1128-1145, 1790 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - #1146, 1147, 1150-1164, 1790 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - #1166-1174, 1176, 1177, 1179, 1180,1184, 1790 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - #1188, 1191, 1194, 1204-1217, 1791 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - #1218-1232, 1791 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - #1233-1241, 1248, 1252, 1259, 1791 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - #1260-1265, 1268-1270, 1791 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - #1271-1277, 1280, 1281, 1283, 1291, 1299, 1791-1792 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - #3113, 3128, unnumbered, 1811 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - #3178, 3205, 3279, 3280, 3307, 1812-1813 (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - #3317, 3337, 3339, 3360, 3363, 3369, 3383, 3403, 3533, 1814-1816 (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - #38, 48-54, 56, 57, 59, 60, 1817 (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - #62-72, 1817 (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - #74-80, 82-89, 1817 (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - #90, 92-100, 1817 (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - #101, 102, 104, 106-111, 1817 (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - #112-121, 123-126, 1817 (Box 4, Folder 59)
  - #127-139, 1818 (Box 5, Folder 60)
  - #140-150, 152-155, 1818 (Box 5, Folder 61)
  - #156-170, 1818 (Box 5, Folder 62)
  - #171-185, 1818 (Box 5, Folder 63)
  - #186-200, 1818 (Box 5, Folder 64)
  - #201-213, 1818 (Box 5, Folder 65)
  - #214-233, 1818 (Box 5, Folder 66)
  - #235-246, 1819 (Box 5, Folder 67)
  - #247-265, 1819 (Box 5, Folder 68)
  - #266-272, 278, 288-290, 1819 (Box 5, Folder 69)
  - #291-295, 297-304, 1819 (Box 5, Folder 70)
  - #305-315, 1819 (Box 6, Folder 71)
  - #317-324, 326, 1819 (Box 6, Folder 72)
  - #327-334, 336-338, 1819 (Box 6, Folder 73)
  - #339-350, 1820 (Box 6, Folder 74)
  - #351-369, 1820 (Box 6, Folder 75)
  - #370-389, 1820 (Box 6, Folder 76)
  - #390-396, 398-406, 1820 (Box 6, Folder 77)
  - #407-416, 1820 (Box 6, Folder 78)
  - #417-434, 1821 (Box 6, Folder 79)
  - #435-450, 1821 (Box 6, Folder 80)
  - #451-466, 1821 (Box 6, Folder 81)
  - #467-481, 483, 484, 1821 (Box 6, Folder 82)
  - #486-495, 4979, 499, 500, 502, 1821 (Box 6, Folder 83)
  - #505, 507, 508, 510-517, 519-526, 1821 (Box 7, Folder 84)
  - #527-537, 1822 (Box 7, Folder 85)
  - #538-544, 547, 1822 (Box 7, Folder 86)
  - #548-557, 1822 (Box 7, Folder 87)
  - #558-567, 1822 (Box 7, Folder 88)
  - #568-577, 1822 (Box 7, Folder 89)
  - #578-587, 1822 (Box 7, Folder 90)
  - #589-597, 1822 (Box 7, Folder 91)
  - #598-605, 607, 1822 (Box 7, Folder 92)
  - #618-624, 626, 627, 1822 (Box 7, Folder 93)
  - #628-636, 1822 (Box 7, Folder 94)
  - #628-636, 1822 (Box 7, Folder 95)
  - #637-642, 644-650, 1823 (Box 7, Folder 96)
  - #651-660, 1823 (Box 7, Folder 97)
  - #661-670, 1823 (Box 7, Folder 98)
  - #671-683, 685-689, 1823 (Box 7, Folder 99)
  - #690-693, 695-699, 701, 703-707, 709, 1823 (Box 7, Folder 100)
  - #711-713, 715-725, 1823 (Box 8, Folder 101)
  - #726-740, 1823 (Box 8, Folder 102)
  - #741, 742, 745-751, 1823 (Box 8, Folder 103)
  - #752, 754, 757-764, 1823 (Box 8, Folder 104)
  - #765-780, 1824 (Box 8, Folder 105)
  - #781-796, 1824 (Box 8, Folder 106)
  - #797-812, 1824 (Box 8, Folder 107)
  - #813, 814, 816-822, 824-830, 1824 (Box 8, Folder 108)
  - #831, 833-840, 842-845, 1824 (Box 8, Folder 109)
  - #846-849, 853-857, 859, 860, 1824 (Box 8, Folder 110)
  - #861-865, 868, 871-878, 1824 (Box 8, Folder 111)
  - #879-888, 890, 891, 1825 (Box 8, Folder 112)
  - #892-898, 900-906, 1825 (Box 8, Folder 113)
  - #907-910, 915-921, 1825 (Box 8, Folder 114)
  - #922-931, 933-935, 944, 946, 948, 1825 (Box 8, Folder 115)
  - #950-953, 955, 958, 961-965, 967-970, 972, 973, 977, 980, and 2 unnumbered, 1825 (Box 9, Folder 116)
  - #983, 984, 990, 1002-0114, 1011, 1022, 1029, 1033-1035, 1041, 1044, 1056, 1058, 1826 (Box 9, Folder 117)
  - #1061, 1062, 1064-1068, 1070-1077, 1826 (Box 9, Folder 118)
  - #1078-1088, 1826 (Box 9, Folder 119)
  - #1089-1093, 1095-1099, 1101-1106, 1827 (Box 9, Folder 120)
  - #1107-1111, 1113, 1114, 1116-1121, 1123-1127, 1827 (Box 9, Folder 121)
  - #1128-1140, 1827 (Box 9, Folder 122)
  - #1141-1150, 1827 (Box 9, Folder 123)
  - #1151-1155, 1157-1161, 1827 (Box 9, Folder 124)
  - #1162, 1164-1174, 1827 (Box 9, Folder 125)
  - #1175-1178, 1180-1187, 1189, 1190, 1827 (Box 9, Folder 126)
  - #1191-1195, 1197, 1199, 1201, 1202, 1204, 1205, 1828 (Box 9, Folder 127)
  - #1206, 1208-1223, 1828 (Box 10, Folder 128)
  - #1224-1231, 1233, 1828 (Box 10, Folder 129)
  - #1234-1236, 4 unnumbered, 1828 (Box 10, Folder 130)
  - #1237-1239, 1241, 1242, 1245, 1250, 1266, 1829 (Box 10, Folder 131)
  - #1276 (fragment), 1282, 2 unnumbered, 1830 (Box 10, Folder 132)
  - #1224 (revised), 1294, 1295, 1299, 1301, 4 unnumbered, 1831 (Box 10, Folder 133)
  - #1310, 1312, 1832 (Box 10, Folder 134)
  - #1319, 1321, 1323, 1324, 1326, 1327, 1833 (Box 10, Folder 135)
  - 16 unnumbered sermons, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 136)
  - Sermon fragments, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 137)
  - Charges to new ministers (10 items), 1822-1830, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 138)
  - Discourse at ordination of EH by Joseph Huntington; with Charge by Mr. Judd and Right Hand of Fellowship by Mr. Williams, 1779 (Box 10, Folder 139)